

AVANA VANA Senior Product Designer & Full-stack Developer

New York, NY +1 347 652 8635 ✓ avana.vana@pm.me
∅ www.avanavana.com
In linkedin.com/in/avanavana

SUMMARY

Senior/Lead Product Designer and Full-Stack Developer with 15+ years experience designing and building production web and mobile apps. Proven track record of shipping best-in-class work and maintaining complex design systems, as a team member, team leader, and independent contractor. Expert in Figma, Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, and a wide variety of modern web frameworks and programming languages such as React, React Native, Next.js, JavaScript, Typescript, and Node.js. I excel especially at distilling complex and/or embryonic brand and product ideas into highly-refined, intuitive user experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FILES.COM JUL 2024 - DEC 2024

UI/UX Designer & Front-end Engineer

Remote

- O Singlehandely planned and executed a re-design & ground-up, section-by-section, line-by-line refactor of all aspects of Files.com's primary Next.js-based marketing website from Chakra UI & CSS modules to TailwindCSS & Radix UI-based components, re-organized its Prismic-based CMS, & systematized the new designs into a Figma library, over the course of 9 weeks.
- Designed a complex, responsive animation for Files.com's marketing homepage and implemented it in React with Framer Motion.
- Worked closely with team of front-end engineers to triage (in code) various customer-facing issues and ship two major features in five months for Files.com's flagship React-based SaaS product, along with delivering designs for the new features.
- built a comprehensive design system & asset library from the ground-up for Files.com's flagship SaaS product, re-creating its React-based UI in Figma, allowing for more interoperability between its growing design team and its product & engineering teams.

THE FULL PACKAGE FLUTTERBY OCT 2022 - PRESENT

Co-founder & CTO

New York, NY & remote

- Produced all designs—wireframes, mock-ups, and prototypes, using Figma—and contributed >50% of both front- and back-end React Native and TypeScript code for two new mobile apps in the dating industry.
- Hired & managed a remote team of developers, completing development a month ahead of schedule and under budget.
- Handled all administrative, legal, and organizational tasks relating to the foundation of a new startup.
- Designed, developed, and optimized a complex geospatial search and multivariate matching & scoring algorithm using Google's S2 library and Elasticsearch, resulting in more local and relevant user matches, at less operational cost.

DOUBLE GEMINI MAR 2019 - DEC 2023

Lead Product Designer & Full-stack Developer

New York, NY & remote

- Led product design & development of a suite of web & desktop productivity apps from first principles, iterating through over 500 wireframes and mock-ups, and a comprehensive design system, implemented in React, TypeScript, & ElectronJS.
 - Designed and built multiple iterations of websites for four online productivity training products, resulting in increased sales year over year and ultimately over 8x traffic across all web properties.
 - Collaborated with company CEO to design and iteratively develop productivity training courses, delivery materials, and presentation materials, which collectively resulted in over \$2m in won deals.
- Developed proprietary plug-in for Gmail using Google Apps Script and internal mobile apps for consulting/training clients that resulted in clients saving upwards of 50% in time spent processing emails.

GRO INTELLIGENCE JAN 2014 - APR 2017

Lead Product Designer & Front-end Developer

New York, NY & remote

• As first hire in Gro's NYC software development office, single-handedly designed flagship agricultural and financial data visualization SaaS product and planned and led early stages of front-end development in Node.js & Javascript.

Hired, managed, and mentored a team of designers and developers, helping the company grow from 8 to 50+ employees.

Designed and built multiple iterations of marketing websites and fundraising presentations, helping the company win its first enterprise users and secure Series B funding, with *Forbes* magazine eventually predicting it would reach "unicorn" status.

• Designed dozens of interactive data visualizations for use within Gro's flagship product, a proprietary base map for geospatial visualizations, and organized millions of disparate indicators and data points across hundreds of geographical regions into a single, intuitive user interface.

SELF-EMPLOYED (FREELANCE)

AUG 2005 - MAR 2019 (ON & OFF)

Product Designer, Graphic Designer, & Full-stack Developer

New York, NY & remote

• Led UX research, product design, web design, print, and environmental design for a dozens of companies across tech, retail, and other industries, working closely with founders and clients to transform early business ideas into viable products.

Front-end, back-end, and API development for a wide variety of web applications, including SaaS, B2B & SEO, social networking, freelancer marketplace, e-commerce, and data management products.

ANCIENT WISDOM PRODUCTIONS

JUL 2009 - JUN 2012

Lead Graphic Designer & Front-end Developer

Ithaca, NY & remote

Won 2012 Webby Award (Apps & Software: Lifestyle, Handheld Devices Category) for design of Planned Parenthood's "Pee in Peace" iOS app, as part of its "Out for Health" campaign.

Designed and did front-end development for over 60 different websites, web apps, and mobile apps for several programs and departments of my alma mater, Cornell University, upstate New York non-profits, and local businesses.

Designed and did front-end development for Cornell University's Johnson Museum of Art's 2008 comprehensive website redesign, organizing the successful migration of thousands of digital artifacts from its voluminous collections to a new, custom-built PHP- and MySQL-based content management system.

Helped dozens of local upstate New York businesses with creative website design, print collateral, and environmental graphics.

EDUCATION /

CORNELL UNIVERSITY AUG 2004 - DEC 2008

B.ARCH (5-year—completed in 4.5), Architecture

Ithaca, NY

Graduated with high honors, cumulative GPA of 3.711

Studied abroad in Mexico & Brazil (Summer 2006), Rome, Italy (Fall 2007), and New York, NY (Spring 2008)

Meinig Family Cornell National Scholar, Founded Student Organization, "The Electronic Music Collective".

SKILLS /

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Product Design, UI/UX Design, UX Research, Prototyping, Design Systems, Design Tokens, Accessibility, Data Visualization, Animation, Print Design, Print Production, Full-stack Development, Front-end Development, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Node.js, Python, PHP, React, React Native, Expo, Next.js, Svelte/SvelteKit, Tailwind CSS, Radix UI, Shadcn-ui, Framer Motion, R3F, TanStack, Redux, GraphQL, Prismic, Firebase, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Elasticsearch, AWS (S3, Lambda, EC2, SES, SNS), Google Cloud Platform (Cloud Functions, PubSub, Firestore), Google S2, AI, Tensorflow, Docker, Kubernetes, Serverless, CloudFormation, Terraform, Google Apps Script, Stripe, StreamChat, Unix, bash, zsh, Git, Github, Jira, Sentry, Segment.io, AdMob, GIS, 3D Modeling, AutoCAD